Dave Koppe – I Design, Create, and Develop

Project Manager, Lead Full-stack Web and Mobile Designer/Developer, UI/UX Architect

Web: www.DaveKoppe.com **Email:** koppe96@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.LinkedIn.com/in/davekoppe

A Little About Me

I'm not your average cubicle sitting type of guy. I thrive in creative environments where teams communicate, and ideas are shared. I want to make trends and push the boundaries instead of doing things because everyone else does it. I'm an innovator that wants to improve myself and my team every day. My experience has given me the opportunity to be involved in the full life cycle design/development, collaborating with multiple departments from business planning, storyboarding, marketing, designers, developers, and finally the end users. I work as a team instead of a siloed approach. I can take an idea written on a napkin to turn it into a full production ready product whether it's for web, mobile, print, TV, and wherever you can place it! In my past few roles, I have been tasked with working with business stakeholders to gather required information to create business requirements, UI/UX mockups, and worked with modern technology to implement the solutions. I have also been involved with being a Product Manager to create tasks for others utilizing Agile methodologies. I'm well versed in working with multiple departments to take products from concept to finished products.

Professional Experience

It's Just Social LLC

January 2022 - Present

Independent Consultant

I run the day-to-day operations of multiple SaaS businesses and websites. Being the founder of my own company lets me be involved in all operations from software development, marketing, managing employees, and so much more.

Standard Tasks

- Create UI/UX mockups of websites and mobile applications using Photoshop, Illustrator, and Adobe XD
- Architect the frontend websites utilizing Blazor, JavaScript, MVC
- Architect backend APIs using .net 8 and C#
- Architect SQL server databases
- Design and develop mobile applications using Maui for both Android and iOS phone/tablets
- Design and develop iOS applications using Swift, SwiftUI, and Firebase
- Architect solutions for IoT devices utilizing .net 8 and C#

Technologies Used

xHTML/HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript jQuery LESS Bootstrap C# Responsive Design MVC

Firebase .Net Core Photoshop Illustrator TypeScript MAUI Xamarin Adobe XD Figma Blazor Swift SwiftUI

GitHub Razor Entity Framework

After Effects Premier

Rauland Ametek May 2023 – July 2024

Project Manager, Lead Full-stack Web and Mobile Architect, UI/UX Architect

I'm a full-stack software engineer working on enterprise applications built with Blazor, C#, Angular, and SQL server databases. I do everything from frontend design and development using the latest web based technologies along with designing and developing Maui Mobile applications for Android/iOS.

Standard Tasks

- I have worked with mobile-based solutions as well as web-based solutions. I worked with mobile based hardware and software solutions in medical and educational environments.
- I'm well versed in agile methodologies using Jira and Confluence
- I have created use cases, acceptance criteria's, test plans, and product documentation for other teams as well as end users.
- Create UI/UX mockups of web/mobile interfaces using Photoshop, Adobe XD, Illustrator,
 Figma
- Architect frontend websites utilizing Blazor
- Architect backend APIs using .net 8 and C#
- Architect SQL server databases
- Design and develop mobile applications using Maui for both Android and iOS phone/tablets
- Design and develop iOS applications using Swift, SwiftUI, and Firebase
- Lead and mentor junior developers
- Maintain internal websites using Angular 17+, C#, MVC, and .Net Core
- Perform Code Reviews

Technologies Used

xHTML/HTML5 CSS3 **JavaScript** LESS **jQuery** Bootstrap C# Responsive Design MVC .Net Core Photoshop Angular MAUI Illustrator TypeScript Xamarin Adobe XD Figma Swift SwiftUI Blazor Firebase Git Azure CI/CD **Entity Framework** Razor

ECRI

Senior Full-stack Web Designer/Developer, UI/UX Architect

My day-to-day job was to take business requirements, create low fidelity/high fidelity prototypes and mockups, converting them to fully functional features/websites. Involved with everything from creating mockups, developing the frontend code, implementing the backend, and creating the databases. Part of an Agile team, our methodology was Scrum

Standard Tasks

- Design/Develop/Enhance/Maintain frontend and backend responsive websites
- Work with business stakeholders, designers, developers, and end users to take business requirements from concept to finished products
- Ensure cross-browser/device compatibility
- Research, reverse engineer, and fix defects.
- Implement TDD using xUnit and Moq
- Maintain internal websites using React, C#, MVC, and .Net Core
- Lead and mentor junior developers

Technologies Used

xHTML/HTML5CSS3JavaScriptjQueryLESSBootstrapC#Responsive DesignMVC.Net CorePhotoshopIllustratorTypeScriptAdobe XDReact

Razor

W.R. Berkley

October 2017 – May 2021

Senior Full-stack Web Designer/Developer, UI/UX Architect

Working as a full-stack designer/developer has given me the ability to use the latest technologies to provide online solutions for customers to purchase insurance policies online. My day-to-day job was to take business requirements, create low fidelity/high fidelity prototypes and mockups, then convert them to fully functional features/websites. Involved with everything from creating mockups, developing front-end code, developing backend code, and creating databases. Part of an Agile team, our methodology was Scrum

Standard Tasks

- Create low fidelity/high fidelity prototypes and mockups
- Implement A/B testing
- Perform usability testing
- Design, develop, maintain frontend and backend responsive websites
- Work with business stakeholders, designers, developers, and end users to take business requirements from concept to finished products
- Ensure cross-browser/device compatibility
- Research, reverse engineer, and fix defects.
- Implement TDD using Specflow and nUnit
- Architect web applications using Angular 13+, MVC, C#, .Net Core, and SQL server

- Design and develop Xamarin mobile applications for iOS and Android
- Perform Code Reviews

Technologies Used

xHTML/HTML5CSS3JavaScriptjQueryLESSBootstrapC#Responsive DesignMVC.Net CorePhotoshopIllustratorTypeScriptAdobe XDXamarin

Angular Razor

Chamberlain Group, Inc.

September 2014 – October 2017

Full-stack Web Designer/Developer, UI/UX Architect

Working as a full-stack designer/developer has given me the ability to use the latest technologies to provide online solutions for customers to purchase insurance policies online. My day-to-day job was to take business requirements, create low fidelity/high fidelity prototypes and mockups, then convert them to fully functional features/websites. Involved with everything from creating mockups, developing front-end code, developing backend code, and creating databases. Part of an Agile team, our methodology was Scrum

Standard Tasks

- Create low fidelity/high fidelity prototypes and mockups
- Perform usability testing
- Design, develop, maintain frontend and backend responsive websites
- Work with business stakeholders, designers, developers, and end users to take business requirements from concept to finished products
- Ensure cross-browser/device compatibility
- Research, reverse engineer, and fix defects.
- Architect web applications using MVC, C#, .Net, and SQL server
- Design and develop Xamarin mobile applications for iOS and Android
- Maintain iOS application utilizing Swift
- Perform Code Reviews

Technologies Used

xHTML/HTML5CSS3JavaScriptjQueryLESSBootstrapC#Responsive DesignMVC.Net CorePhotoshopIllustratorTypeScriptXamarinKnockoutjs

Swift SignalR

Medline, Inc

June 2013 – September 2014

IS-Sys Analyst & Developer II, UI/UX Architect

Being the only frontend developer asset, I have the opportunities to not only be a front runner with frontend development on their main E-Commerce website, but also have opportunities to assist in multiple (external/internal) web-based products targeting multiple devices such as

Desktop, Tablets, Smart Phones, and RF Scanners. Part of an Agile team, our methodology was Scrum

Standard Tasks

- Create low fidelity/high fidelity prototypes and mockups
- Design, develop, maintain frontend responsive websites
- Work with business stakeholders, designers, developers, and end users to take business requirements from concept to finished products
- Ensure cross-browser/device compatibility
- Research, reverse engineer, and fix defects.
- Architect web applications using ASP.net, C#, .Net, and SQL server

Technologies Used

xHTML/HTML5	CSS3	JavaScript
jQuery	ASP.net	Illustrator
C#	.Net	Photoshop

Monotype June 2007 – March 2013

Full-stack Web Designer/Developer, UI/UX Architect

Working on fonts.com opened a wide opportunity to design and develop creative and intuitive methods to search for and purchase fonts. Since the target audience of the E-Commerce website is creative users, aesthetics was crucial to the success of the website. Creative experimentation was encouraged but keeping in mind the standards of E-Commerce websites. Part of an Agile team, our methodology was Scrum

Standard Tasks

- Create low fidelity/high fidelity prototypes and mockups
- Design, develop, maintain frontend responsive websites
- Work with business stakeholders, designers, developers, and end users to take business requirements from concept to finished products
- Ensure cross-browser/device compatibility
- Research, reverse engineer, and fix defects.
- Architect web applications using ASP.net, C#, .Net, and SQL server

Technologies Used

HTML	CSS	JavaScript
jQuery	ASP.net	Illustrator
C#	.Net	Photoshop
Flash	WCF	Ajax
JSON	SQL Server	

Synergy June 2005 – June 2007

Full-stack Web Designer/Developer, UI/UX Architect

Synergy's SaaS website is a human resource information system (HRIS). Working on the SaaS was heavily involved with interacting and showing data to the user. Working with large amounts of

data and the challenges of making the site usable was an important learning factor. Optimizing and maintaining efficiency of the code was a high priority.

Standard Tasks

- Design, develop, maintain frontend websites
- Work with business stakeholders, developers, and end users to take business requirements from concept to finished products
- Ensure cross-browser/device compatibility
- Research, reverse engineer, and fix defects
- Architect web applications using ASP.net, C#, .Net, and SQL server
- Developed auto-generated pdf files for dynamic forms
- Architected a content management system (CRM) for internal employees to maintain the website
- Created presentations and training videos for clients to take courses online.
- Design training materials for print

Technologies Used

HTML CSS JavaScript
Actionscript ASP.net Illustrator
VB.net .Net Photoshop
Flash WCF Ajax
JSON SQL Server Encore

After Effects Premier

Hawk Electronics

Full-stack Web Designer/Developer, UI/UX, Print Design

Hawk Electronics was my steppingstone into developing software for the desktop and web. Their website was an E-Commerce website for customers to search and purchase electrical components online. Desktop applications was used by internal employees to maintain the database for the website. Another desktop application was a Vendor Management System which allowed customers to easily reorder parts by scanning barcodes on products. This software streamlined the ordering process for the customer and kept their inventory full.

July 2000 – June 2005

Standard Tasks

- Develop/Maintain an E-Commerce website for new and existing features
- Develop intranet web-based applications for multiple departments. HR (Accounts receivable application for generating past due, 2nd requests, and credit holds which would be automatically faxed to the customer using Castelle FaxPress or printed. Additional departments like Customer Service (Return Material Authorization (RMA) program to speed up the return process and streamline methods from customer service to value added departments for inspection)
- Architect SQL server table structures, views, and stored procedures
- Research, reverse engineer, and fix defects
- Design marketing Material for Print

Technologies Used

HTMLCSSJavaScriptActionscriptASP.netIllustratorVB6.NetPhotoshopFlashADO/ADO.netSQL Server

Education

The Illinois Institute of Art

January 2002 - June 2005

Bachelor's of Fine Arts – Graduated with Honors

Major: Animation & Media Arts

Oakton Community College

January 1999 – January 2002

General Studies

Course Work: Desktop/Web Programming & Graphic Design

My Services

Video EditingMotion GraphicsRotoscopingGreen Screen Editing3D Modeling3D Animation3D PrototypingPrint DesignGraphic DesignUI/UX MockupsLo-Fi/Hi-Fi MockupsWeb Design

Web Development Full Stack Web Development API's

Game Design/Development Mobile Applications

Skills

Development Languages & Concepts

ADO/ADO.Net ASP.Net C#

CSS/LESS Entity Framework HTML/XHTML/HTML5

JavaScript jQuery Ling Knockoutjs MVC Razor SQL SignalR MVVM Web Api Xamarin Boostrap .Net Core Angular Figma nUnit Agile Blazor Scrum React Swift

SwiftUI Maui

Adobe

Acrobat After Effects Audition
XD Photoshop Illustrator
Premier Express Dreamweaver

Character Animator

Microsoft Office Suite SharePoint

Word

Microsoft 360 Power Point Excess Visual Studio SQL Server Access

AutoDesk 3D Studio Max

Unity Unity 3D